thank you for listening to The Grow Your
Life podcast my name is Jeremiah Kowski
and on this podcast we show you how to
grow a online course coaching mentoring
membership business for those of you I
haven't met yet I've been in this
industry for 21 years have built
multiple businesses over $20 million and
I want to walk you through step by step
how you can produce results in this
business whether you're just starting
out how to create your first 5,000
10,000 $225,000
per month growing an email list running
Facebook ads building an audience and
Beyond from that to have a sustainable
business that you only have to work 5 to
10 hours a week to be able to run so you
can quit your corporate job and that's
what we're talking about here today is
how to quit your corporate job let's
dive right into it I am excited to share
this with you
because I while I've been in the
industry for 21 years for those of
you'all that don't know my full
background on this is I actually was
working for other people in corporate
jobs uh in this and I'll tell you
they're as corporate as it comes when it
comes to even in this industry as far as
that goes I started as a video editor uh
but then quickly rose up as a marketing
director and then became a consultant to
a number of companies which is kind of
like running your own business but
you're still subject to what other
people want you to do uh now to this day
I have total time
Freedom uh Financial Freedom um not not
have to worry about when I need to do
things I can decide to do anything
whenever I want with whomever I want I
don't have to take a client if I don't
want to though we would love to work
with people that want to grow a business
uh whether it be an online course a
membership uh coaching program things
like that we'd love to work with you and
help you scale to 10 $20 million if you
want to or just make your first $5 to
$10,000 okay so of course that's all
about me but what does any of this have
to do with you well how do you actually
quit your corporate job to be able to do
this well here's the thing when you work
a corporate job they wire your brain to
be very easily controlled to be
somebody that does what they say and you
will literally do things working a
corporate job that you would not
otherwise do simply because your boss
asked you to how many of y'all have
known that you've done that now there is
a rising up of people that are choosing
not to do those things and of course you
know ethically morally Integrity or
legally you don't want to do certain
things because you can actually be
liable for those and unfortunately a lot
of Corporations they know that and they
can manipulate people to be the Fall Guy
for that type of stuff okay now we're
not going to go as like that dark into
this but what I want to share with you
is this is how do you get out of the
prison because that's what it is it's a
mental prison it's a mind prison you
become a mind slave to somebody else
where they pay you just enough to keep
you working to numb you out so that you
stay
and serve their vision and don't go
after your goals or do very little to do
so so inside of corporate America inside
of corporate in
general your brain is wired against you
being successful on your own because
they want to keep you on the hook to
keep you coming back it's like a cult
it's like what a cult does now here's
the thing it's legal nobody's going to
call it a cult because our economy is
ran on these things but if you really
like break it down it's basically you
you you you are exploiting people to
produce results to pay them just enough
to then make a profit now here's the
thing I have a corporation and I have
people that work for
me now I do I I as somebody who has
worked in a company I encourage them to
have their own businesses I encourage
them to to even if they don't want to
work with us anymore how to do that okay
and that's what I have found is that I
was always encouraged in that but then
secretly you know that's a topic for
another time what I want to tell you is
how you can get out of this thinking
that they've wired your brain towards
they've wired your brain to please
people they've wired your brain to
perform your brain has been
programmed to only do what you are
certain of out of fear of losing your
job a performance review making less
money or being
chastised so can I tell you this you
have to
rewire that part of your brain in order
to be successful now here's one of the
things that I tell everybody when they
start building one of these businesses
and I wish I knew this sooner and I wish
that somebody would have told me this
sooner start your own
thing and where you notice conflicts in
your mindset between starting your own
thing and how operate in your corporate
job you need to integrate those things
and what's going to happen is this you
will not fit in at your corporate job
longterm you may actually be able to use
some of the mindset to rise in the ranks
and increase your pay temporarily but at
some point the breaking point is going
to come where you and this is what
happened to me you get offered a CEO
position this happened multiple times to
me and then they realize oh wait you
have other vision for things because
you're actually not there to serve the
company you're there to serve
yourself and that's not a bad thing
because that means you're unemployable
and you want to be unemployable okay so
already what I'm saying here is you have
to establish a level of healthy
selfishness if you are going to be able
to go into building your own business
and nobody says
this because it's just not sexy and it
goes against what we're taught in
culture and in society don't be selfish
don't be self-centered you they've
actually done research who's they right
but there there's some research I was
listening to a few podcasters and I did
a little bit of some Google searching on
this on my own basically what they found
is is that the best people that
contribute to society and run companies
are about 60 to 70% selfish and 30 to
40% unselfish meaning that 30 to 40% is
what they do for us
others and that's where the value comes
that we give right when I'm when I'm
here in my company I'm giving value for
you but it's ultimately to help my
company grow and to build connection as
far as that goes so one thing that you
got to realize is it's actually healthy
to get a little bit more selfish than
you have been with things okay and then
the next thing is is this is to stop
trying to manage maintain and control
what other people think about you and
realize that as you start building the
skill set to go out there to build your
own business you're going to disappoint
people you're not going to have
everybody be happy with you and they're
not supposed to be okay so what you got
to do is you got to start a stablishing
new habits where you're going to start
operating like a business owner you're
going to start operating like one of
those people who runs a company and
doesn't work for somebody else and makes
a ridiculous amount of money doing so if
you also think that there should be a
limit in the amount of money that you
can make because maybe you don't need to
live off of that much you need to remove
that thing out of your brain and realize
that the only reason why you're going to
make more money 20,000 50,000 100,000 a
month $500,000 a month why would you do
that so that you can ex so that you can
help more people is what it is that's
actually an unselfish thing it's more
selfish to reduce your income to just
your own basic needs it's less selfish
to actually create a ton of wealth so
that you can impact people so that you
can have a team so that you can have a
company and so that you now become the
lender not the borrower and you become
the one that is influencing and you
become a pillar in your community and
people look up to you okay see we don't
talk about this type of stuff when we're
working in corporate jobs sure we might
be able to in certain corporations where
you have certain roles that are publicly
facing like maybe a corporation like
Tesla you're a CEO of that well okay
there you go CEO of Tesla Elon musk
richest man in the world but you're not
Elon Musk okay you might be smarter than
him by the way I I have met people that
I'm like I guarantee you they're smarter
than Elon
Musk but you're not doing the stuff he's
doing okay so what you got to do is you
got to get realistic about where you're
at today okay then what are you going to
build a business around so we got
different business models that we teach
people on how to do um you can find that
uh throughout some of the other podcasts
I got a bunch of videos on my YouTube
channel as well you can look up my name
on that but the one that I love the most
is uh a membership subscription where
people pay you monthly maybe 100
200 even uh upwards to $500 to $1,000 a
month to get access to you and value and
what it is is you're charging for the
output that they're going to get so if
somebody invests $200 a month with you
they're they they they should easily be
getting $2,000 to $5,000 a month of
value out of that a lot of my clients
get above and beyond exponentially more
than that they get they get close to 20
to $30,000 a month which means like I
should be charging at least $2 to $3,000
a month just for the value that's
produced we we do for some of our higher
level one-on-one coaching stuff for our
Consulting you know we we we we charge
even more than that with our Consulting
clients we've been able to create value
upwards of over a million dollar a month
I be I should be charging $100,000 a
month for those clients
10% what they're making and it's not
unreasonable to say that because if
they're bringing in a million dollars a
month in profit 10% of that because I
was able to produce that for them the
value is there but here's the thing I
often offer things on a value level
generally if a client is making maybe a
million dollar a month I might charge
them you know 20,000 30,000 a month and
and and I think that that's reasonable
that's an extreme discount it's only 2
to 3% of what they're making of of that
okay so but as far as that goes You got
to change your mindset about what it
means to make money and to be successful
and how we interact with other people
and
realize that it starts with a vision of
where you're going and what are you
creating okay so you have to have a
vision that's big enough for everybody
else to come into that's going to be in
your sphere of influence and your vision
has to be longer term possibly for the
next 75 to 100 years that's generational
okay
I got visions that are way bigger than
multiple generations for me and my
family and I'm excited to execute on
them and a big part of that is exactly
this right now helping you be successful
in your own business okay but what
that's great and all to have your own
business and have a product and have
something that you're offering people
but how do you split your time and make
enough money in the business and how do
you operate to be a to leave a corporate
job well what you got to do is you got
to get clients and you got to get people
paying you money but here's the thing is
that when your focus is split and you're
working a corporate job your energy is
going to it's being sucked right into
somebody else's
pocketbook and I'll tell you this is
that if you start to operate in a no BS
attitude where you're not going to take
Guff from anybody you're not going to
let anybody push you
around you may get fired from your job
but it might be the best thing that's
ever happened to you as far as that goes
and then from there you'll have the
energy to be able to go build your
business or you can make enough money in
the business to leave nine times out of
10 what I see people do is is one of two
things they they actually I very rarely
do I see people making enough in their
business to then leave their corporate
job and so I'm just going to level with
you here and tell you that that's the
reality is you'll either be fired or you
need to leave or cut your hours to
parttime as soon as possible in your
corporate job and that's what I would
recommend cut your hours part time see
if you can get paid the same amount for
working half as much time now you got
half as much energy and you're in
control 50% more than you were before
okay that's what I always did when I
would transition out of certain roles
and stuff like that and and I took the
slow route I wish I took this the faster
route because I'll tell you this
is that the strategies the energy me
showing up to the level that I need to
for my clients was limited anytime I was
also serving another person's goals and
visions and I've not had a a a full
period where I've not been serving
somebody else's goals and Visions until
very
recently and so as far as that goes who
am I serving my clients who listen to
this podcast the people who are in my
grow your life Community where that
where I get to work with them to build
their business as far as that
goes but you got to realize that how
you've been programmed inside of your
corporate job is not going to serve you
when it comes to building a business and
this is one of the biggest problems
people have with leaving a corporate job
is because they've been programmed one
way and they literally got to
rewire everything about almost their
entire like personality when it comes to
business
to be able to be successful and one of
them is you cannot worry about what
anybody thinks about
you you also have to embrace making
mistakes you have to become okay with
taking risks and things not going how
you thought they would or how you want
them to and learn to let go of trying to
control the outcome as closely as you
normally would inside of a corporate job
and this is one of the number one things
that people literally find impossible to
do
because they've been wired to do this
inside of their corporate job and if
you're working a corporate job on the
side of this it's nearly impossible to
rewire the brain to be able to operate
differently because you're operating in
one way over here and then you tell
yourself you're going to operate in
another way over here how you do one
thing is how you do everything and so
you're going to have to integrate your
behavior bring combine them together in
both places where you're not business
owner over here and then employee over
here be the business owner let everybody
know that you're doing that and that's
one of the things that I find people say
well I can't let people know that I'm
running my own business well why is that
why are you letting fear run your life
what are you trying to avoid why am I
get fired okay well then maybe just
maybe we need to start a transition
plan to get you out
of that mind control that you've been
under where you let a person paying your
paycheck dictate what you're allowed to
do with your
life h
and I want you to realize this if you've
been working a corporate job what I just
said violates what you feel is normal
behavior but I'll tell you this there is
nobody that could pay me enough to tell
me what I can and can't do with my
life and you got to adopt that attitude
and that mindset if you want to go to
the next level in your business now
we're not going to be Reckless or
flippant and not be able to pay our
bills or our mortgage or things like
that but it takes literally Reinventing
Your yourself as a person saying listen
I might have signed up at this job as
this person here today I'm a different
person and so if you want to work with
the new version of me here's what we're
going to do and and it's going to work
for both of us or I'm going to go find
something else and I'm going to go focus
on that and that's one of the things
I've always had that conversation inside
of businesses is I've always started to
seed the idea of what I'm going to do
I've always started to talk about that
one of the biggest things that people
say is well don't tell anybody what
you're doing and build and see secret
and don't tell anybody what's going on
so people can't kill your dreams of
course don't let silly people kill your
dreams don't let people tell you that
but I'll tell you this it becomes way
more honest when you start telling
everybody what you're actually building
what you're actively doing especially if
they start wondering what the heck is
wrong with you if they start wondering
what's going on why are you behaving
differently and you start being honest
with that you know my life got changed
four months ago 5 months ago when my
wife came home and told me that she was
pregnant with our second
child and I'm excited for that and but
but but it it set me on a path where I
realized I got to change some things I
lost clients because of that they told
me I was taking my family too seriously
and I need to take their their business
projects more seriously and you know
what I told them listen I don't think
we're a good fit to work
together and that's the attitude you
need to have where you will not allow
somebody simply because they are paying
you money or because they make more
money than you or they have more
experience than you or more Talent than
you to be able to run and control your
life it's time for you to start to
create and design your life how you want
it to be and that's one of the first
steps to getting out of the corporate
Rat Race and being able to have your own
business that pays you is you got to
start thinking like a CEO start thinking
like an owner start thinking like a
business owner and no longer like an
employee that just does what you're
told but rather Breaks the Rules makes
the rules bends the
rules and creates your reality instead
of letting other people dictate what
your reality looks like you know reality
is actually what we create of it and and
that's a topic again for another
time you have to work on What's between
your two ears for this stuff to work
it's really all a mindset thing when it
comes to leaving corporate and going
into a business I can give you all the
strategies and our coaching program we
work with people through that we got
hundreds of podcast episodes they give
you strategies but if you don't get this
mindset thing down where you're actually
willing to put yourself out there and
you make a decision I'm not going to be
under the mind
control of another person or
organization simply because they're
paying me
money and you have that Authority and
you have that boundary and you make that
decision for yourself you start caring
yourself differently you start talking
differently some of y'all might see the
the confidence and the conviction of how
I'm talking is different than how it was
six months
ago that's what I'm talking about and
that's what happens when people come
into my space and they
start listening to me engaging with my
podcast they start joining some of the
live events that we're hosting upcoming
events about building a business they
start watching my YouTube videos where I
break down strategies for free for you
to build a business and they they they
join my coaching program to actually
help have me come into their business
and help them build it so that they're
not doing it by themselves so they
actually have somebody who has a proven
track record to work with them through
all of this that's what creates results
okay so I want to encourage you in this
you don't have to go about it alone you
don't have to try to figure this out on
your own that's why I'm here I'm here
and committed to help you and I'd love
to answer your questions on this listen
go to my social media go over to my
YouTube channel go ask me some questions
that you'd love to see us submit in
future podcasts related to this topic to
help you get out of that corporate Rat
Race and start to live the life that you
want all right if this episode has
helped you pass it on to somebody don't
keep it to yourself share it with
somebody and I cannot wait to see you on
the next episode of The Grow Your Life
podcast we'll talk soon
[Music]
[Applause]